{

  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. The fluid gains _________ while passing through the impeller.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Velocity",
        "b": "Pressure",
        "c": "Temperature",
        "d": "Velocity and pressure"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. What is the shape of the diffuser in the centrifugal pump?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Round",
        "b": "Dough nut",
        "c": "Rectangle",
        "d": "Cylindrical"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"3. When the casing in a centrifugal pump decelerates the flow, what increases?",
      "answers":{
        "a": "Pressure",
        "b": "Temperature",
        "c": "Volume",
        "d":"Flow Rate"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"a",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },{
      "question": "4. The velocity imparted by the impeller is converted into _________",
      "answers":{
        "a": "Pressure energy",
        "b": "Kinetic energy",
        "c": "Momentum",
        "d": "Potential energy"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"5. The consequence of Newtons second law is_________",
      "answers":{
        "a": "Conservation of angular momentum",
        "b": "Conservation of mass",
        "c":"Conservation of potential energy",
        "d": "Conservation of kinetic energy"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"a",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Euler developed the head pressure equation in centrifugal pumps.",
      "answers":{
        "a":"True",
        "b": "False"
        
      },
      "correctAnswer":"a",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"7. What is a major advantage of centrifugal pump?",
      "answers":{
        "a": "Cost",
        "b":"Simple in construction",
        "c": "Efficiency",
        "d": "Pump parameters"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"b",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"8. Centrifugal pumps are used to transport ________",
      "answers":{
        "a":"Pressure",
        "b":"Speed",
        "c":"Power",
        "d":"Fluid"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"d",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"9. Different velocities in a centrifugal pump are determined by using ________",
      "answers":{
        "a":"Velocity triangle",
        "b":"Reynolds number",
        "c":"Froude number",
        "d":"Overall efficiency"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"a",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"10. With the increase in the input power, efficiency _______",
      "answers":{
        "a":"Increases",
        "b":"Decreases",
        "c":"Same",
        "d":"Independent"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"b",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    }
  ]
  }